

EMAIL: roselloryan@gmail.com

PHONE: 813.545.2666

GITHUB: www.github.com/roselloryan

TWITTER: @roselloryan

BLOG: www.medium.com/@roselloryan **LINKEDIN:** www.linkedin.com/in/roselloryan

Ryan ROSELLO



BIO

Jazz took me around the world teaching me about patterns, people, and art. Pre-med curriculum and medical research taught me about science, math and the human condition. After working as an insurance biller for a physical therapy clinic, I decided to return to school to study medicine. I found coding along the way while studying for the MCAT. It was an enjoyable relief from studying anatomy, med school applications and seemingly brought together all of my past experiences in a way I had never experienced before.

After brief introductions to HTML, Python, and JavaScript on Codecademy, I met with various types of programmers to get a better idea of different career paths. I was most excited by the iOS engineers work and knew this was my next step. I enrolled in the immersive iOS development course at the Flatiron School and have spent every day since working to learn the skills needed to be a valued mobile developer and contributing team member.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

<u>Celsius and Fahrenheit</u> - Current temp in °C and °F with animated illustrations for weather conditions for cities around the world. Available in the App Store.

- + References OpenWeatherMap API to access current weather conditions for +200k cities
- + Persists data using Core Data framework
- + Utilizes MapKit framework for user to select city if more than one location has the same name
- + Features all original illustrations with charming animations SceneKit parti
- + iOS Today extension using Core Location framework displays current city, temps and weather condition icon
- + GitHub repository

<u>Project Mailbox</u> - Bringing intimacy back to social media. Invitation only groups for sharing pictures, songs, thoughts, or drawings.

- + Utilized Parse cloud based data storage for user content storage and retrieval
- + Implemented iOS Share extension to post songs to our app from within Spotify app
- + Integrated Spotify iOS SDK to allow in app streaming of shared Spotify songs
- + Used third party framework to allow users to create and post drawings

Space POD App - displays NASA picture of the day plus sounds from space to amaze and inspire.

- + Fetches Astronomy picture of the days from NASA api
- + Retrieves, stores, and plays tracks from NASA SoundCloud playlists
- + Incorporates various animations for floating playback buttons



Ryan ROSELLO RESUME

EDUCATION

Columbia University, 2014

Certificate in Premedical Sciences, Healthcare/Research

University Of North Florida, 2006

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Music/Jazz studies

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

T2	Mu	ltis	port	NYC

New York, NY

Systems Manager/USA Cycling Coach

Feb. 2015 - Sept. 2015

- + Set up computers and calibrate sensors for 18 training stations that measure power output
- + Tested athlete power output and endurance to quantify performance change
- + Improved cyclists' FTP (functional threshold power) and power to weight ratio (W/Lb)
- + Designed power zone training sessions that increased rider FTP by 30% over 6 months time

Miccass Physical Therapy

New York, NY

Physical Therapy Aide

Dec. 2014 - Sept. 2015

- + Led patients, one on one, through physical therapy programs to help heal and regain function
- + Demonstrated proper technique for stretches and exercises preventing injury
- + Adjusted program intensity for patients to safely gain strength and flexibility
- + Verified insurance authorization details for accurate billing

NYU School Of Medicine at Bellevue Hospital

New York, NY

Emergency Research Volunteer (PAVERS)

August 2013 - May 2015

- + Screened and enrolled patients in active studies to decrease patient exposure to radiation
- + Processed data from abdominal and cardiac ultrasound scans including vitals, blood levels, findings and final diagnosis
- + Assisted physicians with emergency procedures in trauma bay
- + Performed patient electrocardiogram tests (ECG, EKG)

Sports Physical Therapy Of New York

New York, NY

PCS/Biller

August 2010 - April 2012

- + Maintained patient treatment information authorizations, prescriptions, and plans of care
- + Audited treatment notes for accurate treatment times and CPT codes
- + Scheduled patient appointments and applied account payments
- + Initiated successful employee fitness challenge